♪I lean and gaze at misty waves afar♪
♪Tears fall on the ancient road
'neath the setting sun♪
♪One lone shadow on the cold river♪
♪In dreams, I return to the old window♪
♪Mountains stretch, the road home fades♪
♪A flute cries out, hooves hurry on♪
♪My heart adrift beneath a frosted moon♪
♪Drinking alone, I mourn our parting♪
♪Night turns cold, wind stirs the veil♪
♪Old robes recall forgotten days♪
♪Heart sore, a lone goose flies south♪
♪Where shall I send this letter?♪
♪Lost in thought through endless nights♪
♪Love runs deep, dreams linger on♪
♪Only sorrow remains♪
♪A cup of wine, my shadow makes us two♪
♪Drunk and lost through flashing blades♪
♪I curse how swiftly the years pass by♪
♪The wandering road goes on♪
♪Desolate, time frosts my youthful hair♪
♪Through the years, love still burns♪
♪A thousand tears fall♪
♪Worlds apart, tears stain my sleeves♪
♪Old dreams haunt my heart,
tears cloud my eyes♪
♪Heartbroken, soul-worn,
pain won't fade♪
♪Moonlight westward, the night drags on♪
♪The years have left their scars♪
♪Autumn winds sweep leaves;
shadows pair♪
♪The past fades like smoke;
tears fall♪
♪My heart lies broken♪
♪Lost in thought through endless nights♪
[Love Legend]
[Episode 14]
Rebels?
Sir.
Could it be
Yun Shao?
Whoever planted the Gu
has made no move yet.
Maybe they're planning another trap.
- Commander Xiao.
Carry on.
Sir.
You're no longer with the Fengyi Bureau.
No need to salute me.
Sir.
Brother, get up.
Don't kneel.
Get up.
Now that you're leading the rebels,
we're enemies.
We're only meeting today
to exchange info.
Nothing more.
I need to find this man.
He was a miner at the Blood Jade Mine
and vanished 18 years ago.
Yes.
I will find him at once, my lord.
Xiao Ruoming.
You're no longer
with the Fengyi Bureau.
You should
stop calling me that.
I have something else to report.
Ruoli found a secret tunnel
at Mingyu Headquarters.
It leads
to the back of Xing'en Temple.
Sir.
This is the altar behind Xing'en Temple.
Strange.
What is?
Mingyu used ordinary white jade,
but this is blood jade.
Why would the Yuns
sacrifice Yun Shao with blood jade?
Right.
Blood-jade rituals are only for royalty.
Could it be...
I'm going to see His Majesty.
[Illustrious Virtue]
Your Majesty.
Please take a closer look.
Does she remind you of someone?
Well...
My eyesight is failing.
I can barely see.
You came to see me
just to show me
this portrait?
Your Majesty.
Please look carefully.
Pei Zhao.
Where did you get
this portrait of the Empress
before her marriage?
Are you certain, Your Majesty,
that this is the Empress?
The late Empress and I grew up together.
How could I not recognize her?
Do you have a portrait of her?
I'd like to see it.
How dare you?
Don't mistake my trust
for permission to overstep.
Your Majesty.
The woman in this portrait
is the younger Lady Yun,
Yun Shao.
She's the same age as the Crown Prince.
On the day of his Blood Jade Ritual,
the Yuns were draining Yun Shao's blood
with blood-jade hairpins.
Yun Shao escaped,
and the Crown Prince's ritual failed.
I'll give you a secret edict.
Find out what happened.
If anyone tampered
with the royal bloodline,
show no mercy.
Yes.
On the day of his Blood Jade Ritual,
the Yuns were draining Yun Shao's blood
with blood-jade hairpins.
Yun Shao escaped,
and the Crown Prince's ritual failed.
I'll give you a secret edict.
Find out what happened.
If anyone tampered
with the royal bloodline,
show no mercy.
Father.
Lord Pei.
Lord Yun.
I'm here to take Lady Yun
to the Fengyi Bureau for questioning.
Shao just returned.
Her mother cannot bear to part with her.
Bring her back early
after you're done.
Master, bad news.
Master.
The Young Master was attacked.
They just found him outside the city,
covered in blood.
Hurry.
You did it?
If I had,
I'd have done it here.
Then which hero did?
I should thank him.
Six months ago,
the capital began such rites.
Young nobles gathered at night,
cut girls and bleed them into wine.
Yun Qi was especially fond of it.
He often hosted
Blood Banquets.
What an animal.
Unfortunately,
none of those nobles will testify.
And with all this attention,
Yun Qi won't risk another Blood Banquet.
Here.
Our gallant hero.
Next time,
cover your tracks better.
So you found my pendant.
Madam Yun made this herself.
I can't lose it.
That explains it.
So our Chang'an beat up Yun Qi.
That weakling?
I only hit him five times
and he started crying.
And someone like that
commands the garrison?
Enough.
Stop bragging.
Go play.
Madam Yun and I
have business to discuss.
General Chang'an, take care.
Sir.
Do you
have business with me?
There's a wishing tree
east of the city.
I'd like
to take you there.
To make a wish?
[Fortune]
You have wishes too?
No.
Like you,
I want to find those innocent girls.
If every official in Yong were like you,
the people would be blessed.
When the ruler is virtuous,
the people may prosper.
Speaking of the ruler in public?
Someone may report you.
♪Moon shadows flicker and sway♪
♪A wisp of longing haunts the air♪
- Let's go.
- Sir, you're blushing.
I'm not.
Why would I?
You are.
Here.
And here.
Stop it.
Fine.
You were kept inside since childhood.
Do you remember much?
Did anyone unusual visit you?
Did anyone give you anything special?
No.
I stayed in the back courtyard
and rarely went to the front.
Animals.
Sir.
You're acting strange today.
Is something bothering you?
I went to where you were sacrificed.
Is this yours?
Mother gave it to me
for my Flowering Rite.
You call this a gift?
Hey.
Don't throw it away.
Blood jade is valuable.
We could sell it.
It's filthy.
Don't wear it.
If you want blood-jade jewelry,
I'll buy you some.
Oh.
Sir, madam.
You mustn't say such things.
Blood Jade must not be bought or sold.
Why not look at these accessories?
All the latest styles from the capital.
We're not buying Blood Jade.
Just looking.
Pack them all.
Right away.
You really spoil your wife.
Wait.
Not that one.
Sir, don't throw it away.
I can sell it
to someone else.
It's bright red.
No one should wear it.
Getting upset?
Don't be.
[Tablet of My Lost Son]
Why won't my son come
to me in dreams?
Let me see you once more.
Your Highness.
The Crown Prince is here.
Greetings, Mother Consort.
Perfect timing.
I had some portraits sent over
of ladies of marriageable age.
See if any please you.
Mother Consort.
There's already
someone I like.
Please help me marry her.
Is that so?
Which family's daughter?
Tell me.
The younger Lady Yun.
Yun Shao.
Have you lost your senses?
She was abducted by ruffians.
Her reputation is ruined.
How can she be Crown Princess?
I will wed no one but her.
Calm yourself, Your Highness.
Your Highness.
Prince of Xin'an has arrived.
All of you, leave.
Why such anger?
It's bad for your health.
I thought you'd never
come see me again.
I wouldn't dare.
I value my head.
So you are afraid of something.
You've got some nerve.
You've been back this long
and haven't visited once.
What?
Think you don't need
my support anymore?
I've been busy
with you
and the Crown Prince.
Go.
Kill Yun Shao for me.
Because
the Crown Prince wants to marry her?
You know already?
Do you have spies
around me?
You were shouting so loudly.
I heard you from outside the palace.
Calm down.
I say
just let him marry her.
Once Yun Shao enters the Eastern Palace,
she'll be under your control.
After the Blood Jade Ritual,
you can dispose of her
however you please.
That mind of yours
does come in handy.
Your Majesty.
You've said lately
that your vision is failing.
I've prepared a medicinal decoction
to help your eyes.
Even the imperial physicians
can't help my eyes.
A few sips of decoction?
What good will that do?
Tell me.
What is it?
You may all leave.
Qingyan came to me.
He said he likes a woman
and wants to marry her.
Which family is she from?
The younger Lady Yun.
Yun Shao.
The woman in this portrait
is the younger Lady Yun,
Yun Shao.
Her?
I'm not trying to benefit the Yuns.
This was Qingyan's own idea.
He's always
been good and obedient.
This is the first time
he's ever asked me for anything.
I couldn't refuse him.
I thought
if the late Empress were watching,
she wouldn't want Qingyan unhappy.
I plan
to make Yun Shao a junior consort
and grant Qingyan his wish.
Later,
we can choose someone suitable
as Crown Princess.
Would that be acceptable?
Your Majesty.
The third of next month is auspicious.
I was thinking
of holding the Crown Prince's
and Pei Zhao's weddings together.
Yun Qi has little talent.
We can't rely on him later.
But Pei Zhao is different.
He's brave and clever.
Once they are in-laws,
Pei Zhao will
devote himself
to the Crown Prince.
Go back for now.
Let me think about it.
♪A cold blade gleams by the window♪
♪Candle tears harden into frost♪
♪Moon shadows flicker and sway♪
♪A wisp of longing haunts the air♪
♪A lone boat rests on the misty river♪
♪That promise lies sealed with my sword♪
♪I turn to find the world in snow♪
♪Fated destiny ties from bygone life♪
♪Longing for one beloved flows on♪
♪I can't let go of the verses lost
across this vast land♪
♪Yet I let go of that fleeting light
within your eyes♪